peoplesound.com 2006-12-30

# Privacy Policy - Peoplesound

|  |  |   
---|---|---  
---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---  
|  |   
|  |  |  |  |  |  |  | |  | 

## PEOPLESOUND.COM PRIVACY POLICY

Peoplesound.com Ltd is registered under the Data Protection Act 1998  
Registered number: Z8393171  
---|---|---|---  
| 

## 01.

|  | 

## Introduction

At Peoplesound we recognize that privacy is an important issue. This Privacy Policy outlines the types of personal information we gather when you use our services, as well as some of the steps we take to safeguard your personal details. When you register with Peoplesound.com, you are doubly opted-in to our services. This means that once you have registered and clicked on the submit button (and checked the relevant boxes for the B!Music Newsletter or third party emails), you have opted in once. We will then send you a confirmation email with an activation link in it to verify your email address - once you click on this, you have opted-in twice.  
| 

## 02.

|  | 

## You can opt that we cannot collect personal data in the first place:

In order to ensure we are not collecting data about you, you must either disable the cookie feature on your browser or leave the site by clicking on the back button on your browser until you leave Peoplesound.com. If you subsequently contact us by e-mail at [general@peoplesound.com](mailto:general@peoplesound.com), we will be happy to confirm that we are not holding data about you and to delete from our records any data that we may have. If you would like us to remove all information and data collected about you from our records, please send a blank e-mail to [general@peoplesound.com](mailto:general@peoplesound.com) with the word REMOVAL in the "Subject" field. Please note that if you remove your details you will no longer be able to take advantage of many of the features the site has to offer. By continuing to use this web site, you thereby give your consent to us collecting and processing personal information.  
| 

## 03.

|  | 

## Data Transfer Outside the European Economic Area:

Your personal information may also be sold, traded or rented to third parties who may be located outside the European Economic Area, including to countries which may not have data protection laws, in order to enable them to send you details that they think will interest you, including by way of direct marketing. By submitting your personal details to us you consent to this transfer. The information that you submit may be transferred outside the European Economic Area for processing by peoplesound.com and its associated companies and to maintain accounts for you at other peoplesound.com sites. By supplying personal data to us, you consent to this transfer. If you do not want your information transferred outside the European Economic Area at any time, please send a blank e-mail to [general@peoplesound.com](mailto:general@peoplesound.com) with the words EUROPEAN ECONOMIC AREA in the "Subject" field.   
| 

## 04.

|  | 

## What and How Do We Collect Information about you and How Is It Used?:

Information on the music you are streaming and downloading and the artists you are searching for/against in our database. Your general use of the site will provide us with may also be collecting information on which tracks you forward to friends (but not details about your friends!!) and which pages of the site you visit. This information may be used by us or given to third parties for their use on an aggregated or individual basis, including for use in direct marketing campaigns providing that you gave us permission to do so at registration.  
| 

## 05.

|  | 

## Supply of Registration Data to Third Parties:

When you register with us to use our services or receive products you will need to input a variety of information, including (but not limited to) your name, e-mail address, post code, age, gender, music preferences and such other information as you will be requested to supply from time to time on our registration form. With your permission, this information may be used by us or given to third parties for their use, including for use in direct marketing campaigns.  
| 

## 06.

|  | 

## Will We Disclose the Information We Collect to Third Parties?:

Sometimes we might use the information to let you know about functionality changes to our web site, new goods, services or offers that you might find interesting. We may, at our discretion, choose to sell, trade or rent your personal information to trustworthy third parties such as other record companies and other companies who may use that information for direct marketing purposes unless you have informed us that you do not want this to happen. 

In addition, Peoplesound.com may provide aggregate statistics about our sales, customers, traffic patterns and other site information to third parties, but these statistics will not include any information that could personally identify you. 

Peoplesound.com reserves the right to access and disclose individually identifiable information to comply with applicable laws and lawful government requests, to operate its systems properly or to protect itself or its users.   
  
| 

## 07.

|  | 

## Use of Information for Competitions:

If you enter a contest or promotion we will ask for your name, address and e-mail address and any other information that we consider relevant to the competition. This is so we can administer the contest and inform the winners. This information may be used by us or given to third parties for their use, including for use in direct marketing campaigns, unless you have informed us that you do not want this to happen.  
| 

## 08.

|  | 

## Use of Artist Information:

If you are an artist who has submitted your music to Peoplesound via the artist submission area, we will have collected as much data as you provided us with on completing your submission. We will also collect data with regard to the use of your music on our websites. All such information will be used by our music team to make judgements about your music for the purposes of classifying it into genres and sub-genres of music and marking it for retrieval by our site navigation systems, by our editorial team for describing you and your music and by our marketing team for marketing purposes (including giving the information to third parties for the purposes of direct marketing initiatives), with your permission.  
| 

## 09.

|  | 

## How Do We Protect Your Information?

When you review your account information or order products from us, we offer the use of a secure server. The secure server software encrypts the information that you input before it is transmitted to us. In addition, we have strict security procedures covering the storage and disclosure of your information in order to prevent unauthorised access to comply with the data protection law. This means that sometimes we may ask for proof of identity before we disclose personal information to you.  
| 

## 10.

|  | 

## Cookies:

A cookie is a piece of information that is stored on your computer's hard drive by your web browser. On revisiting Peoplesound, our computer server will recognise the cookie, giving us information about your last visit. Most browsers accept cookies automatically, but usually you can alter the settings of your browser to prevent automatic acceptance. If you choose not to receive cookies, you may still use most of the features of our website, including purchasing items.  
| 

## 11.

|  | 

## Ad Serving:

Our Web site uses ad servers (such as Real Media) to serve the advertisements that you see on pages of our Web site. That partner uses cookies to help target ads to you. To find out more about the use of cookies and the information-gathering practices and opt-out procedures of Real Media, please [click here](http://www.247realmedia.com/about/247RM_Code-of-Conduct.pdf?navSource=TopNav) to download the PDF. Real Media's Privacy Policy can be found [here](http://www.247realmedia.com/privacy.html).  
|    
  
|   
|    
|
